Shawn **Zimmermann**

Summary _____

Currently finishing a master's degree. Have research experience in designing correct high performance distributed systems. 6+ years of experience with C and modern C++, 3+ years of experience with Go, Java, Python. Plan to continue systems research.

Education

University at Buffalo

Buffalo, NY USA

Jan 2021 - June 2024

B.S and M.S. in Computer Science and Engineering

· Specializing in Distributed Systems

Research Experience ____

Generalized Systems Evaluation Framework

April 2023 - Present

CPI NETWORKED SYSTEMS LAB: ADVISED BY HAONAN LU AND ZHUOYUE ZHAO

- Building a general automated framework for distributed transactional systems evaluation gRPC/Thrift/Java/Go
- Identifying pain points in the existing methods of systems evaluation
- Preliminary study on existing systems by evaluating Eiger-PORT on Emulab
- · Created and gave presentations on operating systems, processes, and networking concepts to new student researchers

Data Provenance in Microkernel Notebooks

Buffalo, USA

ONLINE DATA INTERACTIONS LAB: ADVISED BY OLIVER KENNEDY

October 2022 - Present

- Implemented data provenance in microkernel notebooks and dependency tracking between notebook cells Python/Scala
- · Investigated managing uncertain data within data sets, and getting notebook kernels to share state more efficiently

Work Experience _____

Bolt Graphics, Inc.

Remote USA

SOFTWARE DESIGN ENGINEER (FULL-TIME)

October 2021 - March 2023

- Developed modular software variant of initial Bolt Graphics raytracing platform C++
- Developed custom GPU drivers for clients GPU to interact with Bolt hardware C/Vulkan 1.2
- Delivered software implementations of the Research and Development teams investigations and surveys

University at Buffalo

Buffalo, NY USA

Systems Programming Teaching Assistant

August 2021 - Present

- Created and gave supplementary lectures on the use of the UNIX command line
- · Hosting lab sessions where students implemented short programs designed to show them the necessary systems programming skills

Projects _____

Raft Distributed Consensus Algorithm

CLASS PROJECT

- Implemented the algorithm described in the "In Search of an Understandable Consensus Algorithm" research paper Go
- Designed and implemented multiple RPC calls for communication between nodes gRPC
- Designed a testing suite with Go's testing package to check each functionality for correctness

MakeOpenSource Operating System

GitHub Link

CLUB PROJECT

October 2022 - Present

- · Assisted in developing and advising development on an educational open source operating system C/Assembly
- Assisted the MakeOpenSource club implement common open source industry best practices

Binary Data Visualization Tool

GitHub Link

PERSONAL PROJECT

- CLI tool to assist in debugging binary output C
- Designed to be to 'xxd' combined with 'diff' with the addition of color for easier readability

OCTOBER 30, 2023 SHAWN ZIMMERMANN · RÉSUMÉ